Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going out to eat.
今天我们要出去吃饭。
Yes, good thing too because I'm hungry.
是啊，正好我也饿了。
I know, it's almost lunchtime.
我知道，快到午饭时间了。
Yeah.
嗯。
So today we're going to be talking about eating at a restaurant and giving some great recommendations
所以今天我们要讨论在餐厅吃饭，并给出一些很好的推荐
and suggestions.
和建议。
Yes, we have language for describing food, for describing restaurants and for making
是的，我们有描述食物、描述餐厅以及提出建议的语言。
suggestions.
建议。
Great, so let's start with our vocabulary preview for this lesson.
太好了，那么让我们从这节课的词汇预览开始。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We have two words today from our dialogue which you'll need to know to understand the
今天对话中有两个词你需要知道才能理解
dialogue.
对话。
Great.
好的。
The first one that we have today is food poisoning.
今天第一个词是食物中毒。
Food poisoning.
食物中毒。
So food poisoning is...
所以食物中毒是……
Not a good thing.
不是好事。
It is when you eat some bad food and that food makes you sick.
就是当你吃了变质的食物，那食物让你生病。
So you get food poisoning.
所以你食物中毒了。
Okay, so food poisoning, yeah, not a good thing.
好的，食物中毒，嗯，不是好事。
Okay, the next word.
好的，下一个词。
Allergic.
过敏。
So when you're allergic to something...
所以当你对某样东西过敏时……
It makes you sick.
它会让你生病。
That one thing makes you sick.
那样东西让你生病。
For example, I'm allergic to seafood.
比如，我对海鲜过敏。
If I eat seafood, I cannot breathe.
如果我吃了海鲜，我就无法呼吸。
Oh, okay, so you definitely want to stay away from fish.
哦，好的，那你肯定要远离鱼了。
Yes, yes.
是的，是的。
Some people are allergic to nuts, like peanuts.
有些人对坚果过敏，比如花生。
Or maybe milk.
或者牛奶。
Milk.
牛奶。
Yeah.
嗯。
Cool.
酷。
So when one type of food makes you sick, you are allergic to that food.
所以，当一种食物让你生病时，你就对这种食物过敏。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So with this in mind, now we can listen to our dialogue for the first time at its normal
那么，记住这一点，现在我们第一次以正常速度听对话。
speed.
速度。
But don't worry if you don't get everything now because...
但如果你现在没完全听懂也别担心，因为……
We'll come back and teach you the important language.
我们会回来教你重要的语言点。
Do you two have any plans for the evening?
你们俩今晚有什么计划吗？
We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the neighborhood.
我们正考虑去附近的一家餐馆看看。
Do you have any suggestions?
你有什么建议吗？
I know this really nice Italian place.
我知道一家很不错的意大利餐厅。
The food is fantastic and the decor is beautiful.
食物很棒，装修也很漂亮。
I'd recommend giving it a try.
我推荐你去试试。
Actually, I'm not all that crazy about Italian food.
其实，我对意大利菜没那么热衷。
I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter.
我想吃点清淡的。
In that case, I know a great little bistro.
那样的话，我知道一家很棒的小酒馆。
They make a really tasty seafood platter.
他们做的海鲜拼盘非常好吃。
The fish is outstanding.
鱼做得特别出色。
It sounds fantastic, but I'm allergic to seafood, so...
听起来很棒，但我对海鲜过敏，所以……
Okay, well, let me think.
好吧，让我想想。
Oh, I know this great little place.
哦，我知道一家很棒的小店。
It's just a hole in the wall, but they do the most amazing sandwiches.
那家店虽然不起眼，但他们做的三明治超级好吃。
You could give them a try.
你可以去试试。
Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning, remember?
艾拉，上次我来的时候你带我去过那里，结果我食物中毒了，还记得吗？
Well I'm getting hungry just thinking about all of those great restaurants.
光是想想那些好餐厅我就饿了。
Yeah, some really good recommendations except for food poisoning, right?
是啊，推荐得都不错，除了食物中毒那次，对吧？
No, not so good.
不，那次不太好。
Let's start with our language takeaway for this lesson.
让我们开始这节课的语言要点吧。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Our first word on language takeaway is check out.
语言要点的第一个词是 check out。
Check out.
Check out。
So we have some great examples on how we can use check out in different situations and
所以我们有一些很好的例子，展示如何在不同情况下使用 check out，
then you can understand the meaning.
然后你就能理解它的意思了。
Example one.
例子一。
Have you been to the new cafe next door?
你去过隔壁那家新开的咖啡馆吗？
Yeah, I checked it out yesterday.
去过，我昨天去看了看。
The food was great.
食物很棒。
Example two.
例子二。
Hey, check out my new car.
嘿，看看我的新车。
Example three.
例子三。
I'm going to check out that new shopping mall this weekend.
我这周末要去看看那个新开的购物中心。
So I can understand that it just means look at.
所以我能理解它只是表示“看”的意思。
Yeah, look at or yeah or go see.
对，就是“看”或者“去看看”。
So let's go check out that new bar in town.
那我们去看看镇上那家新开的酒吧吧。
Yeah, okay, cool.
好，没问题。
Next word is bistro.
下一个词是bistro。
Bistro.
Bistro。
So what's a bistro?
那么什么是bistro？
It's kind of complicated, but it's like a small restaurant that's not really cheap though.
有点复杂，但就像一家小餐馆，不过不是很便宜。
Not so cheap, but not so expensive.
不算便宜，但也不算贵。
And it's usually French.
而且通常是法式的。
Yes.
是的。
So yeah, small informal restaurant.
所以，就是小型非正式餐馆。
Yeah, bistro.
对，bistro。
Okay, so our third phrase for today is not all that crazy about.
好的，那我们今天的第三个短语是not all that crazy about。
Not all that crazy about.
Not all that crazy about。
I'm not all that crazy about.
I'm not all that crazy about。
Okay, again, kind of a funny phrase, but we've got some examples that will help you understand
好的，这个短语有点有趣，但我们有一些例子可以帮助你理解
the meaning.
它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
Do you want to go shopping with me tomorrow?
你明天想和我一起去购物吗？
I'm not all that crazy about shopping.
我不太喜欢购物。
I don't like spending money.
我不喜欢花钱。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm not crazy about jazz music.
我不太喜欢爵士乐。
Can I change the song?
我能换首歌吗？
So this is just a really polite way of saying you don't like something.
所以这是一种非常礼貌的表达不喜欢的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
But now the opposite of this would be tasty.
但它的反义词是tasty。
Tasty.
Tasty。
That's our fourth word, tasty.
这是我们的第四个词，tasty。
Tasty.
Tasty。
So when something is tasty, it's good.
所以当某样东西tasty，就是好吃。
It's good.
好吃。
Like delicious.
比如美味。
Delicious.
美味。
Yeah.
是的。
You know what?
你知道吗？
In English, we almost never say the food is delicious, but we always say it's really
在英语中，我们几乎不说食物很美味，而是常说它很
tasty.
好吃。
Yes.
对。
This is really tasty.
这个真好吃。
Yes.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Tasty.
好吃。
And our last phrase for language takeaway, in the mood for.
我们语言摘录的最后一个短语是“有心情做某事”。
In the mood for.
有心情做某事。
Let's listen to some examples of this phrase and we'll understand the meaning a little
我们来听一些这个短语的例子，这样就能更好地理解它的意思。
bit better.
更好一点。
Example one.
例子一。
We always eat hamburgers for dinner.
我们晚餐总是吃汉堡。
I'm in the mood for something different.
我想吃点不一样的。
Example two.
例子二。
Let's watch a movie.
我们看电影吧。
How about Texas Chainsaw Massacre?
《德州电锯杀人狂》怎么样？
I am not in the mood for a horror movie.
我没心情看恐怖片。
So if I'm in the mood for something, I feel like doing or eating or watching.
所以如果我说“有心情做某事”，就是我想做、想吃或想看什么。
It means you want to do that now.
意思是你现在就想做那件事。
Yeah.
对。
I'm in the mood for.
我有心情做某事。
Okay.
好的。
Some great language we just looked at.
我们刚刚学了一些很棒的语言点。
And I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time.
我想是时候再听一遍对话了。
Do you two have any plans for the evening?
你们俩今晚有什么计划吗？
We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the neighbourhood.
我们正考虑去附近的一家餐馆看看。
Do you have any suggestions?
你有什么建议吗？
I know this really nice Italian place.
我知道一家很不错的意大利餐厅。
The food is fantastic and the decor is beautiful.
食物很棒，装修也很漂亮。
I'd recommend giving it a try.
我推荐去试试。
Actually, I'm not all that crazy about Italian food.
其实，我对意大利菜不太感兴趣。
I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter.
我想吃点清淡的。
In that case, I know a great little bistro.
那样的话，我知道一家很棒的小酒馆。
They make a really tasty seafood platter.
他们做的海鲜拼盘非常好吃。
The fish is outstanding.
这鱼非常好吃。
It sounds fantastic.
听起来很棒。
But I'm allergic to seafood, so...
但是我对海鲜过敏，所以……
Okay.
好吧。
Well, let me think.
嗯，让我想想。
Oh, I know this great little place.
哦，我知道一家很棒的小店。
It's just a hole in the wall, but they do the most amazing sandwiches.
那家店虽然不起眼，但他们做的三明治超级好吃。
You've got to give them a try.
你一定要去试试。
Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning, remember?
艾拉，上次我来的时候你带我去过那家店，结果我食物中毒了，还记得吗？
Okay, some really great and useful phrases there.
好的，这里有一些非常棒且实用的短语。
And I know you want to talk about specifically some of these phrases.
我知道你想专门谈谈其中的一些短语。
Yes.
是的。
So, today's lesson is all about making recommendations, right?
那么，今天的课程全是关于如何提出建议，对吧？
Right.
对。
So, let's look at some useful phrases in Fluency Builder.
我们来看看“流利度构建器”中的一些实用短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So, in the dialogue, we heard a great way of asking for a suggestion.
在对话中，我们听到了一种很好的寻求建议的方式。
That's right.
没错。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Do you have any suggestions?
你有什么建议吗？
So, that's how you would ask for a suggestion.
这就是你寻求建议的方式。
Or you can say something else like, do you have any ideas?
或者你也可以说别的，比如“你有什么想法吗？”
Yeah, or you might say, do you have any thoughts?
是的，或者你可以说“你有什么看法吗？”
Okay, so that's asking for suggestions.
好的，这就是寻求建议。
In response to this, you can say something like this.
对此，你可以这样说。
I'd recommend giving it a try.
我建议你试一试。
We also heard another phrase that we use for giving suggestions.
我们还听到了另一个用于提出建议的短语。
You've got to give them a try.
你一定要去试试。
So, these two phrases are great.
这两个短语都很棒。
I'd recommend or you've got to give them a try.
“我建议”或者“你一定要去试试”。
Yeah.
是的。
Great ways of suggesting.
很好的建议方式。
Yes.
是的。
Now, what's really important here is the pronunciation of these words, right?
现在，这里非常重要的一点是这些单词的发音，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
You'll notice that we don't say I would recommend.
你会注意到我们不会说“I would recommend”。
Right.
对。
We use the contraction I'd.
我们使用缩写 I'd。
I'd.
I'd。
I'd recommend.
我推荐。
Similarly, in the phrase, you have got to, we shorten that to say, you gotta.
同样，在短语中，you have got to，我们缩短为 you gotta。
You gotta.
You gotta。
You gotta give them a try.
你得试试它们。
You gotta.
You gotta。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
You know what, guys?
你们知道吗？
If you can shorten your phrases like this, if you can push the sounds together, you'll
如果你能像这样缩短短语，把音挤在一起，你
sound a lot more natural, hey?
听起来会更自然，对吧？
And also, you'll be able to understand because in movies or in shows, they will never say,
而且，你也能听懂，因为在电影或节目中，他们从不会说
you have got to give them a try.
you have got to give them a try。
Yeah.
是的。
So, if you can do it in this form, you'll understand what they mean.
所以，如果你能用这种形式，你就能明白他们的意思。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
很好。
Well, why don't we listen to the dialogue a third time and you'll hear some of these
那么，我们何不再听一遍对话，你会听到一些
contractions in the dialogue.
对话中的缩写。
Do you two have any plans for the evening?
你们俩今晚有什么计划吗？
We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the neighborhood.
我们正考虑去附近的一家餐馆看看。
Do you have any suggestions?
你有什么建议吗？
I know this really nice Italian place.
我知道一家很不错的意大利餐厅。
The food is fantastic and the decor is beautiful.
食物很棒，装饰也很漂亮。
I'd recommend giving it a try.
我推荐去试试。
Actually, I'm not all that crazy about Italian food.
其实，我对意大利菜不太感兴趣。
I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter.
我想吃点清淡的。
In that case, I know a great little bistro.
那样的话，我知道一家很棒的小餐馆。
They make a really tasty seafood platter.
他们的海鲜拼盘非常美味。
The fish is outstanding.
鱼非常出色。
It sounds fantastic, but I'm allergic to seafood, so...
听起来很棒，但我对海鲜过敏，所以……
Okay.
好吧。
Well, let me think.
嗯，让我想想。
Oh, I know this great little place.
哦，我知道一家很棒的小店。
It's just a hole in the wall, but they do the most amazing sandwiches.
虽然店面不起眼，但他们做的三明治超级好吃。
You could give them a try.
你可以去试试。
Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning, remember?
艾拉，上次我来的时候你带我去那里，我食物中毒了，还记得吗？
Okay, great dialogue.
好的，很棒的对话。
And Erica, I know that you have some food poisoning stories for us.
艾丽卡，我知道你有一些食物中毒的故事要跟我们分享。
Well, I don't know about stories, but I've definitely had food poisoning before.
嗯，故事倒谈不上，但我确实食物中毒过。
One of the worst times that I ever had food poisoning was when I was traveling in Morocco.
我最严重的一次食物中毒是在摩洛哥旅行的时候。
I had some really amazing orange juice, really fresh, squeezed that day in the morning.
我喝了一些非常棒的橙汁，非常新鲜，是当天早上现榨的。
And then I got on a bus.
然后我上了一辆公交车。
Okay.
好吧。
I think you can see where this is going.
我想你知道接下来会发生什么。
Yeah, so I was on the bus and then I started to feel really sick.
是啊，我在公交车上开始觉得很不舒服。
And I was just hoping and hoping and hoping that the bus ride would be over soon.
我一直祈祷、祈祷、再祈祷，希望公交车快点到站。
But unfortunately, it wasn't.
但不幸的是，并没有。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
All I can say is that I was sick.
我只能说，我病得很厉害。
All I can say is that I was pretty sick and really, really unhappy.
我只能说，我病得很重，非常非常难受。
Yeah, I bet.
是啊，我猜也是。
Well, that's very strange that you got sick from orange juice, huh?
嗯，喝橙汁喝到生病，这很奇怪，是吧？
Well, yeah, maybe it was with some dirty water or something like that.
嗯，是啊，可能是用了脏水或者类似的东西。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It was just, it was a terrible situation.
那真是一场可怕的经历。
Yeah, it's always complicated when you're traveling to other countries.
是啊，去其他国家旅行时，情况总是很复杂。
It could be the water.
可能是水的问题。
It could be the way they prepare things.
也可能是他们准备食物的方式。
Yeah.
是啊。
Food poisoning.
食物中毒。
Well, guys, I hope that you don't get food poisoning.
好了，朋友们，希望你们不会食物中毒。
And if you have any food poisoning stories, it would be great for you to share them.
如果你们有食物中毒的故事，欢迎分享。
Yes, at our website, EnglishPod.com.
是的，在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上。
And we'll see you there to answer all your questions and comments.
我们会在那里回答你们的所有问题和评论。
But now we have to go.
但现在我们得走了。
Okay, guys, thanks for listening.
好了，朋友们，谢谢收听。
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
Bye-bye.
再见。